片名：哈利波特： 凤凰会的密令
大家都感觉到吧 今天热死了
I don't know about you, it's just too hot today, isn't it?
而且明天会更热 气温会升到摄氏三十几度
And it's going to get even worse. Temperatures up in the mid-30s Celsius...
就是华氏九十几度 也许会破百
...that's the mid-90s Fahrenheit, tomorrow, maybe even hitting 1 00.
请记得防晒、保持清爽
So, please, remember to cover up and stay cool...
继续收听我们所播出 最热门的音乐
...with the hottest hits on your FM dial.
来吧，该回家了
Come on, guys, time to go home.
宝贝，下来
Come on, love, off you get.
- 一定要回家吗？ - 当然
-Do we have to? -Yes, we do.
我会做你最爱的菜补偿你
l'll make you your favorite dinner to compensate.
他像猪一样尖叫
He squealed like a pig, didn't he?
打得好，达老大，超棒的
Yeah, brilliant punch, Big D. Did you see his face?
嘿，达老大
Hey, Big D.
又在欺负小孩了吗？
Beat up another 1 0-year-old?
- 这小鬼活该 - 是啊
-This one deserved it. -Yeah.
- 五个打一个，好勇敢哦 - 你还敢说我？
-Five against one, very brave. -Well, you're one to talk.
你每晚睡觉都会哀哀叫 至少我不会怕我的枕头
Moaning in your sleep every night? At least l'm not afraid of my pillow.
“不要杀西追”
''Don't kill Cedric.''
西追是谁？你男友吗？
Who's Cedric, your boyfriend?
- 闭嘴 - “妈，他要杀我”
-Shut up. -''He's going to kill me, Mum.''
你妈在哪里？
Where is your mum?
你妈在哪里呀，波特？
Where is your mum, Potter?
她死了吗？
She dead?
她是不是死了？
ls she dead?
她肯定挂了K
ls she a dead Pott--?
- 达力 - 达力，我们走吧
-Dudley. -Dudley, let's go.
- 怎么回事？ - 你在搞什么鬼？
-What's going on? -What are you doing?
- 我什么也没做 - 来吧，达力，快走
-l'm not doing anything. -We're getting out of here, Dudley.
达力，快跑！
Come on, Dudley, hurry up.
Dudley, run.
疾疾，护法现身！
Expecto Patronum.
费太太
Mrs. Figg.
捡起魔杖，哈利
Don't put away your wand, Harry.
他们可能会回来
They might come back.
催狂魔闯入小惠因区 接下来呢？
Dementors in Little Whinging, whatever next?
- 全世界都会一团乱 - 我不懂，你怎么会知道K
-Whole world's gone topsy-turvy. -l don't understand. How do you know--?
邓不利多要我 注意你的安全
Dumbledore asked me to keep an eye on you.
邓不利多？ 你认识邓不利多？
Dumbledore asked you? You know Dumbledore?
那个人去年 杀了可怜的迪哥里
After You-Know-Who killed that poor Diggory boy last year...
你以为他会让你 一个人在外面乱晃吗？
...did you expect him to let you go wandering on your own?
拜托，他们还说你很聪明
Good Lord, boy. They told me you were intelligent.
好了，快进去吧，别出门
Now, get inside and stay there.
很快就会有人来找你 不管怎样都别出门
Expect someone will be in touch soon. Whatever happens, don't leave the house.
真是酷热
It is hot. That's right, hot everywhere.
各地气候都又湿又闷热K
There's sweat. There's stifling.
小达达？
Diddykins?
是你吗？
ls that you?
达达K 威农，快来
Duddy. vernon, come quick.
我们得把他送到医院
We're going to have to take him to a hospital.
这是谁干的好事？
Who did this to you, boy?
好了，现在你高兴了吧？
Happy, are we, now?
这下可好 你终于把他逼疯了
You've finally done it. You've finally driven him loopy.
威农，别说这种话
vernon, don't say that.
看看他，佩妮 我们的儿子中邪了
Well, just look at him, Petunia. Our boy has gone yumpy.
我受不了你了，听到没？
l've reached my limit, do you hear?
我不能再忍受 你的诡异行径了
This is the last l'm gonna take of you and your nonsense.
- 亲爱的波特先生 - 什么？
-Dear Mr. Potter. -What?
魔法部接获情报 今天傍晚六点二十三分
The Ministry has received intelligence that at 6:23 this evening...
你当着一个麻瓜的面 施展护法咒
...you performed the Patronus Charm in the presence of a Muggle.
这种行为严重违反K
As a clear violation...
未成年魔法合理使用限制法规
...of the Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of Underage Sorcery...
霍格华兹魔法与巫术学校K
...you are hereby expelled...
因此决定开除你的学籍
...from Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
祝你安好，玛法达霍克克
Hoping you are well, Mafalda Hopkirk.
老天有眼
Justice.
他不太舒服
He's not very well.
对不起，嘿美
Sorry, Hedwig.
这些麻瓜还满干净的嘛
very clean, these Muggles.
- 东施，拜托好不好 - 太不正常了
-Tonks, for God's sake. -Unnatural.
穆敌教授
Professor Moody.
- 你怎么会来这里？ - 当然是来救你啊
-What are you doing here? -Rescuing you, of course.
我们要去哪儿？ 我被学校开除了
But where are we going? The letter said l've been expelled.
没有，没那么快 金利，你解释
You haven't been. Not yet. Kingsley, you take point.
可是那封信说K
But the letter said--
邓不利多 说服魔法部暂缓执行
Dumbledore persuaded the minister to suspend your expulsion...
- 直到正式听证会举行 - 听证会？
-...pending a formal hearing. -A hearing?
别担心，回总部再跟你说清楚
Don't worry. We'll explain everything when we get back to headquarters.
别乱说话，小仙女
Not here, Nymphadora.
不要叫我小仙女
Don't call me Nymphadora.
大家排好飞行队形 就算有人被杀也不可脱队
Stay in formation, everyone. Don't break ranks if one of us is killed.
你！过来！ 转角的那个！
Come on, you, around the corner.
来吧
Come on.
进去吧，孩子
ln you go, son.
没人看到
There've been no sightings.
没人死，没有证据
No deaths. No proof.
他差点杀了哈利就是证据
He almost killed Harry. lf that isn't proof enough....
话是没错，不过呢K 最重要的是对付那个人
Yes, but guarding you-know-what is the most important....
我们必须信任邓不利多
We must trust Dumbledore on this.
他去年有保护好哈利吗？ 我认为我们应该采取行动了
Was he able to protect Harry last year? Well, tonight l say it's time to take action.
夫子只在乎政治 对他来说，巫师身份是其次
Cornelius Fudge is a politician first and a wizard second.
- 他根本就不会管这件事 - 大家小声点
-His instinct would be to ignore it-- -Keep your voices down.
那个人的力量愈来愈强 我们一定要马上行动
He's getting stronger and stronger by the minute. We have to act now.
- 哈利 - 卫斯理太太
-Harry. -Mrs. Weasley.
感谢老天，你没事
Heavens, you're all right.
有点憔悴 不过会议结束才能吃晚餐
Bit peaky, but l'm afraid dinner will wait until after the meeting's finished.
别问，我没时间解释 你先上楼，左转第一道门
Nope. No time to explain. Straight upstairs, first door on the left.
对了
Yeah.
麻种、狼人、叛徒
Mudblood, werewolves, traitors, thieves.
还有小偷，如果女主人 知道这些人渣来她家K
lf my poor mistress knew the scum they let into her house...
会跟我怪角说什么呢？
...what would she say to old Kreacher?
真是可耻
Oh, the shame.
- 怪胎 - 别生气，女主人
-Freaks. -There, there, mistress.
低级的人渣，真是世风日下
Scum of the earth. Not like it was in the days of my fathers.
我怪角永远都会在
Kreacher is here.
哈利
Oh, Harry.
你没事吧？ 我们偷听到催狂魔攻击的事
Are you all right? We overheard them talking about the Dementor attack.
- 快告诉我们经过 - 先让他喘口气吧，妙丽
-You must tell us everything. -Let the man breathe, Hermione.
还有魔法部听证会 太过分了
And this hearing at the Ministry. lt's just outrageous.
我查过，他们不能开除你
l've looked it up. They simply can't expel you.
- 太不公平了 - 没错
-lt's completely unfair. -Yeah.
外面发生了很多事情
There's a lot of that going round at the moment.
这是什么地方？
So, what is this place?
- 这里是总部 - 凤凰会的总部
-lt's headquarters. -Of the Order of the Phoenix.
凤凰会是个秘密社团
lt's a secret society.
邓不利多当年 对抗那个人的时候创立的
Dumbledore formed it back when they fought You-Know-Who.
你们不能写信告诉我，对吧？
Couldn't have put any of this in a letter, l suppose?
整个暑假都没你们的消息
l've gone all summer without a scrap of news.
我们很想写信 真的，不骗你
We wanted to write, mate. Really, we did.
- 只是K - 只是什么？
-Only.... -Only what?
邓不利多要我们发誓 不能告诉你
Only Dumbledore made us swear not to tell you anything.
邓不利多这么说？
Dumbledore said that?
他干嘛瞒着我？ 也许我能帮忙
But why would he keep me in the dark? Maybe l could help.
毕竟是我看到 伏地魔回来的
l'm the one who saw voldemort return...
是我跟他打斗 亲眼看到迪哥里被他杀死
...the one who fought him, who saw Cedric Diggory get killed.
- 哈利 - 你讲话还是这么温和
-Harry. -Thought we heard your dulcet tones.
- 别压抑，兄弟，发泄出来 - 发泄完了K
-Don't bottle it up, though, mate. Let it out. -lf you're all done shouting....
想听些有趣的事情吗？
Do you wanna hear something a little more interesting?
哈利最有权利知道事实
If anyone has a right to know, it's Harry. If it wasn't for Harry...
没有他 没人会知道伏地魔回来了
...we wouldn't even know Voldemort was back.
他不是孩子了，茉莉
He's not a child, Molly.
可是他也还不算是大人
But he's not an adult either.
- 他不是詹姆，天狼星 - 他不是你儿子
-He's not James, Sirius. -Well, he's not your son.
我把他当成儿子
He's as good as.
- 他没有亲人了 - 你好，金妮
-Who else has he got? -Hey, Ginny.
- 他还有我 - 好感人的父爱，布莱克
-He's got me. -How touchingly paternal, Black.
也许波特长大也会变成罪犯 就跟他的教父一样
Perhaps Potter will grow up to be a felon, just like his godfather.
你不要插话，石内卜
Now, you stay out of this, Snivellus.
- 石内卜也是凤凰会成员？ - 讨厌鬼
-Snape's part of the Order? -Git.
有关你那所谓的改革
--about your supposed reformation.
- 我知道怎样对他最好 - 那你干嘛不跟他说？
-I know better. -So why don't you tell him?
- 不能吃 - 快
-Get off it. -Quick.
- 拉上来 - 歪腿！
-Get it up. -Crookshanks.
- 不可以 - 走开，臭猫
-Stop it. -Get off, you bloody cat.
- 歪腿，别乱来 - 拉上来
-Crookshanks. Leave it alone. -Get it up.
- 妙丽，我讨厌你的猫 - 坏猫猫
-Hermione, l hate your cat. -Bad Crookshanks.
我们要在厨房吃饭
Well, we'll be eating down in the kitchen.
你们现在可以使用魔术
Just because you're allowed to use magic now...
不代表你们可以 拿着魔杖胡闹！
...does not mean you have to whip your wands out for everything.
嗨，妈
Hi, Mum.
饿了吗，哈利？
You hungry, Harry?
你真的没事？我们都很担心
You sure you're all right, Harry? Gave us quite a turn.
哈利波特
Harry Potter.
天狼星
Sirius.
这真是太奇怪了
This is very, very peculiar.
你在魔法部的听证会 巫审加码所有的成员都会出席
lt seems your hearing in the Ministry is to be before the entire Wizengamot.
我搞不懂 魔法部对我有什么不满
l don't understand. What has the Ministry of Magic got against me?
给他看吧 反正他迟早会知道
Show him. He'll find out soon enough.
（骗人的男孩？）
他也在抨击邓不利多
He's been attacking Dumbledore as well.
（夫子说一切平安）
夫子用尽他所有的力量 包括在《预言家日报》的影响力
Fudge is using all his power, including his influence at the Daily Prophet...
抹黑宣称见到黑魔王回来的人
...to smear anyone who claims the Dark Lord has returned.
为什么？
Why?
部长认为邓不利多 觊觎他的工作
He thinks Dumbledore's after his job.
太夸张了，疯子才会相信K
No one in their right mind could believe that--
这就是重点 夫子已经神智不清
Exactly the point. Fudge isn't in his right mind.
他的脑袋被恐惧给扭曲了
lt's been twisted and warped by fear.
恐惧会让人做出可怕的事情
Now, fear makes people do terrible things, Harry.
上次伏地魔夺得权力
The last time voldemort gained power...
几乎摧毁了我们珍惜的一切
...he almost destroyed everything we hold most dear.
他又回来了 部长会不择手段
Now he's returned, and l'm afraid the minister will do almost anything...
回避面对这个恐怖真相
...to avoid facing that terrifying truth.
我们认为伏地魔 想要重整一支军队
We think voldemort wants to build up his army again.
十四年前他有大批的爪牙
Fourteen years ago, he had huge numbers at his command.
其中不只是巫师 还包括各式各样的黑暗生物
And not just witches and wizards, but all manner of dark creatures.
他正在大举募兵 我们也一样
He's been recruiting heavily, and we've been attempting to do the same.
但他想要的 并不只是爪牙
But gathering followers isn't the only thing he's interested in.
我们相信
We believe...
伏地魔想找一样东西
...voldemort may be after something.
天狼星
Sirius.
上次他没找到的东西
Something he didn't have last time.
你是说武器吗？
You mean like a weapon?
够了，他只是个孩子
No. That's enough. He's just a boy.
再说下去 干脆让他加入凤凰会
You say more and you might as well induct him into the Order.
好啊，我想加入 伏地魔在重整军队，我要参战
Good. l want to join. lf voldemort's raising an army, then l want to fight.
哈利
Harry.
因此决定开除你的学籍
You are hereby expelled.
巫审加码所有的成员都会出席
Before the entire Wizengamot.
在地下开火车
Trains. Underground.
这些麻瓜真是聪明
lngenious, these Muggles.
我们到了
Here we are.
我从来没用过访客入口 应该会很好玩
l've never used the visitors' entrance before. Should be fun.
好吧，我就用我的麻瓜钱吧
Right. Good. l'll just get my Muggle money.
我昨天超倒霉 在魔药市场交易损失惨重
Terrible. Lost a lot of Galleons trading on the potions market.
《预言家日报》，谁要买？
Daily Prophet, ladies and gentlemen. Anybody for Daily Prophet?
（邓不利多是笨还是危险？）
“邓不利多是笨还是危险？”
Dumbledore: ls he daft, or is he dangerous?
- 早安，亚瑟 - 早啊，巴布
-Morning, Arthur. -Morning, Bob.
跨部门备忘录
lnterdepartmental memos.
以前都用猫头鹰送递，脏死了
We used to use owls. Mess was unbelievable.
我的天啊 谢谢你，金利
Merlin's beard. Thank you, Kingsley.
- 他们更改了听证会时间 - 改到什么时候？
-They've changed the time of your hearing. -When is it?
五分钟后
ln five minutes.
神秘部门到了
Department of Mysteries.
部长，我相信 你会做出正确决定
And l'm confident, minister, that you will do the right thing.
没错，不过我们必须K
Yes, but we must be--
记住，听证会上 轮到你再说话
Remember, during the hearing, speak only when you're spoken to.
保持冷静，你没做错事
Keep calm. You've done nothing wrong.
就像麻瓜说的 真相会大白
As the Muggles say, truth will out.
对吧？
Yes?
他们不准我陪你进去
l'm not allowed in, l'm afraid.
祝你好运，哈利
Good luck, Harry.
这是八月十二日的纪律听证会
Disciplinary hearing of the 1 2th of August...
犯案人哈利詹姆波特居住在K
...into offenses committed by Harry James Potter...
萨里郡小惠因区水蜡树街四号
...resident at Number 4 Privet Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.
侦讯人魔法部长 康尼留斯夫子K
lnterrogators: Cornelius Oswald Fudge, Minister of Mag--
我是辩方证人！
Witness for the defense.
阿不思博知维巫服利K
Albus Percival Wulfric...
布莱恩邓不利多
...Brian Dumbledore.
你应该收到 听证会时间地点K
You got our message that the time and place of the hearing...
- 更改的信息，对吧？ - 我一定是错过了
-...had been changed, did you? -l must have missed it.
不过幸好我提前三小时 来魔法部
But by a happy mistake, l arrived at the Ministry three hours early.
罪名是什么？
The charges?
以下是被告的罪名
The charges against the accused are as follows:
他在完全了解
''That he did knowingly...
并且知道 此为违法行为的情况下
...and in full awareness of the illegality of his actions...
在一个麻瓜面前
...produce a Patronus Charm...
施展护法咒
...in the presence of a Muggle.''
- 你是否承认以上的指控？ - 是的，但是K
-Do you deny producing said Patronus? -No, but--
你也知道未满十七岁 在校外K
And you were aware that you were forbidden to use magic outside school...
- 不准使用魔法吗？ - 我知道，可是K
-...while under the age of 1 7? -Yes, l was, but--
各位巫审加码的巫师和女巫
Witches and wizards of the Wizengamot--
催狂魔出现我才会这么做
l was only doing it because of the Dementors.
催狂魔？
Dementors?
跑去小惠因区？
ln Little Whinging?
这是很聪明的借口
That's quite clever.
麻瓜看不到催狂魔，对吧？
Muggles can't see Dementors, can they, boy?
- 这借口真好用 - 我没说谎
-Highly convenient. -l'm not lying.
- 有两个，要是我没K - 够了 ！
-There were two of them, and if l hadn't-- -Enough.
抱歉我要打断 这个编好的故事K
l'm sorry to interrupt what l'm sure would have been a very well-rehearsed story...
但是由于这起事件 没有目击证人
...but since you can produce no witnesses of the event--
部长，其实现场有目击证人
Pardon me, minister, but as it happens, we can.
请描述一下攻击事件
Please describe the attack.
他们长什么样子？
What did they look like?
其中一个很胖，另一个很瘦
Well, one of them was very large and the other rather skinny.
我不是说男孩子们 是催狂魔
Not the boys. The Dementors.
是哦，他们很高大
Oh, right, right. Well, big.
身穿斗篷 然后K四周变得很冷
Cloaked. Then everything went cold...
好像所有的快乐都从世上消失
...as though all the happiness had gone from the world.
大家听我说 催狂魔不会随便跑到麻瓜社区
Now, look here. Dementors don't just wander into a Muggle suburb...
碰巧遇到一个巫师 不可能有这种巧合
...and happen across a wizard. The odds are astronomical.
我想，没有人认为K
l don't think anyone would believe...
催狂魔去那里 只是个巧合，部长
...the Dementors were there by coincidence, minister.
我一定是误解你了，教授
l'm sure l must have misunderstood you, professor.
毕竟催狂魔受到魔法部的控管
Dementors are, after all, under the control of the Ministry of Magic.
这么说很傻 不过你好像暗示K
And it's so silly of me, but it sounded for a moment as though...
攻击事件是魔法部下的命令
...you were suggesting that the Ministry had ordered the attack on this boy.
这的确令人不安 政务次长女士
That would be disturbing indeed, Madam Undersecretary...
所以魔法部一定会进行全面调查
...which is why l'm sure the Ministry will be mounting a full-scale inquiry...
两个催狂魔为何远离阿兹卡班
...into why the two Dementors were so very far from Azkaban...
以及他们为何未经授权发动攻击
...and why they mounted an attack without authorization.
当然一定是有人K
Of course, there is someone...
策动这次攻击
...who might be behind the attack.
康尼留斯，请你看清真相
Cornelius, l implore you to see reason.
黑魔王回来的证据 已经非常明显
The evidence that the Dark Lord has returned is incontrovertible.
他根本没回来！
He is not back.
至于哈利波特的罪名
ln the matter of Harry Potter...
法律明文规定
...the law clearly states...
生命受威胁时 可在麻瓜面前用魔法
...that magic may be used before Muggles in life-threatening situations.
法律可依实际状况而修改
Laws can be changed if necessary, Dumbledore.
为何单纯的未成年使用魔法事件
Clearly. Has it become practice to hold a full criminal trial...
要搞到这样大费周章全面审判？
...to deal with a simple matter of underage magic?
认为他有罪的人请举手
Those in favor of conviction?
认为该撤销所有控诉的人请举手
Those in favor of clearing the accused of all charges?
撤销所有控诉
Cleared of all charges.
教授！
Professor.
兽足，你是不是疯了？
Padfoot. Are you barking mad?
你会害我们的行动曝光
You'll blow the entire operation.
天狼星，你来干嘛？ 如果被发现K
Sirius, what are you doing here? lf somebody sees you....
我一定要向你道别
l had to see you off, didn't l?
人生本来就充满了风险
What's life without a little risk?
我不想看到 你被关进阿兹卡班
l don't wanna see you get chucked back in Azkaban.
不要担心我
Don't worry about me.
拿去，我要把这张照片给你
Anyway, l wanted you to have this.
凤凰会的创立成员
Original Order of the Phoenix.
马琳麦金农
Marlene McKinnon.
拍完这张照片 两周后她就遇害
She was killed two weeks after this was taken.
伏地魔杀死了她全家人
voldemort wiped out her entire family.
法兰克跟艾丽斯隆巴顿
Frank and Alice Longbottom.
奈威的爸妈
Neville's parents.
他们的遭遇比死亡更惨
They suffered a fate worse than death, you ask me.
都已经十四年了
lt's been 1 4 years.
但是我没有一天 不想念你爸爸
And still a day doesn't go by l don't miss your dad.
你觉得有可能会开战吗？
Do you really think there's going to be a war, Sirius?
感觉跟上次很像
lt feels like it did before.
你留着吧
You keep it.
我猜你们是新一代的斗士
Anyway, l suppose you're the young ones now.
火车上见
l'll see you at the train.
再见K
Bye-bye, darling.
我爱你
l love you.
牵好我的手，亲爱的
Hold my hand, lovey.
他们来了 他们在远一点的车厢
There they are. They're in the far carriage.
再见K
Bye.
我很意外魔法部会放你出来
l'm surprised the Ministry's still letting you walk around free.
还有自由的时候 好好享受一下
Better enjoy it while you can.
你迟早会被关进阿兹卡班
l expect there's a cell in Azkaban with your name on it.
- 我早说了，你是个疯子 - 离我远一点！
-What'd l tell you? Complete nutter. -Just stay away from me!
马份就是这样
lt's only Malfoy.
狗改不了吃屎
What'd you expect?
你们好
Hi, guys.
- 嗨，奈威 - 嗨，奈威
-Hey, Neville. -Hey there, Neville.
这是什么？
What is it?
- 什么东西？ - 那个拉马车的东西
-What's what? -That. Pulling the carriage.
没有东西在拉马车啊
Nothing's pulling the carriage, Harry.
马车一直都是自己动的
lt's pulling itself, like always.
你没有发疯
You're not going mad.
我也能看到他们
l can see them too.
你跟我一样没发疯
You're just as sane as l am.
各位，这是露疯子K
Everyone, this is Loony Love--
露娜罗古德
Luna Lovegood.
好有意思的项链哦
What an interesting necklace.
这是咒语项链
lt's a charm, actually.
可以赶走水烟虫
Keeps away the Nargles.
我好饿
Hungry.
希望有布丁吃
l hope there's pudding.
- 水烟虫是什么？ - 不晓得
-What's a Nargle? -No idea.
晚安，孩子们
Good evening, children.
今年的教职员有两项变动
Now, we have two changes in staffing this year.
让我们欢迎葛柏兰教授回来
We're pleased to welcome back Professor Grubbly-Plank...
她将在海格教授离开的期间
...who'll be taking Care of Magical Creatures...
暂时代理奇兽饲育学
...while Professor Hagrid is on temporary leave.
也请欢迎新的 黑魔法防御术老师
We also wish to welcome our new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher...
桃乐丝恩不里居教授
...Professor Dolores Umbridge.
大家都跟我一样 祝教授一切顺利
And l'm sure you'll all join me in wishing the professor good luck.
管理员飞七先生 照常要我提醒各位K
Now, as usual, our caretaker, Mr. Filch, has asked me to remind you--
她有出席听证会 她替夫子工作
She was at my hearing. She works for Fudge.
校长，谢谢你热烈地欢迎我
Thank you, headmaster, for those kind words of welcome.
我很高兴看到这么多亮丽K
And how lovely to see all your bright...
快乐的脸蛋 带着微笑看我
...happy faces smiling up at me.
我相信我们一定会成为好朋友
l'm sure we're all going to be very good friends.
- 是喔 - 是喔
-That's likely. -That's likely.
魔法部最重视的
The Ministry of Magic has always considered...
一向都是年轻巫师和女巫的教育
...the education of young witches and wizards to be of vital importance.
虽然每任校长都会替这所K
Although each headmaster...
历史悠久的学校带来新的创意
...has brought something new to this historic school...
但是绝对不能只为了发展而发展
...progress for the sake of progress must be discouraged.
让我们保存必须保存的一切
Let us preserve what must be preserved...
达到能够达到的完美境界
...perfect what can be perfected...
并且禁止应该禁止的练习课程
...and prune practices that ought to be prohibited.
谢谢你，恩不里居教授 这番话真是令人茅塞顿开
Thank you, Professor Umbridge. That really was most illuminating.
- 拜托，全是一堆废话 - 到底是什么意思？
-llluminating? What a load of waffle. -What's it mean?
在走廊上不准施展魔法K
Magic is forbidden in the corridors....
意思是魔法部 开始干涉霍格华兹了
lt means the Ministry's interfering at Hogwarts.
（波特是阴谋者？）
丁，西莫
Dean, Seamus.
- 暑假好玩吗？ - 还好
-Good holiday? -All right.
至少比西莫好多了
Better than Seamus', anyway.
我妈今年不想要我回来
Me mum didn't want me to come back this year.
- 为什么？ - 该怎么说呢？都是因为你
-Why not? -Let me see. Because of you.
《预言家日报》说了很多关于你 还有邓不利多的事
The Daily Prophet's been saying a lot of things about you and Dumbledore.
你妈居然相信？
What, your mum believes them?
西追死的那晚没有别人在
Nobody was there the night Cedric died.
那就跟你的蠢妈妈一样看报纸 你想要知道的事上面都有
l guess you should read the Prophet, then, like your stupid mother.
- 不准你这样说我妈！ - 谁说我是骗子，我就跟谁单挑
-Don't talk about my mother. -l'll have a go at anyone that calls me a liar.
- 有问题吗？ - 他就是最大的问题
-What's going on? -He's mad, is what's going on.
你相信他说的 那个人的谎话吗？
Do you believe the rubbish he's come out with about You-Know-Who?
对，我相信
Yeah. l do.
还有谁对哈利有意见？
Has anyone else got a problem with Harry?
- 你没事吧？ - 没事
-You all right? -Fine.
西莫真的是太过分了
Seamus was bang out of order, mate.
- 不过他会想通的，等着瞧 - 我说我没事，荣恩！
-But he'll come through, you'll see. -l said, l'm fine, Ron.
好吧，那我就让你静一静吧
Right. l'll just leave you to your thoughts, then.
哈利
Harry.
让它飞过来
Bring it over here. Over here.
西莫，把它打下来
Oh, go on, Seamus. Go on, get it.
早安，孩子们
Good morning, children.
普通巫术等级检测
Ordinary Wizarding Level examinations.
O-W-L-S O-W-Ls.
通常都简称为普等巫测
More commonly known as OWLs.
用功念书就一定会有回报
Study hard and you will be rewarded.
否则下场可能会是一塌糊涂
Fail to do so, and the consequences may be severe.
你们之前的教材品质参差不齐
Your previous instruction in this subject has been disturbingly uneven.
（ 《黑魔法防御术》 ）
不过你们从现在开始
But you'll be pleased to know, from now on...
将学习拥有严谨结构
...you will be following a carefully structured, Ministry-approved...
经过魔法部核准的防御术课程 什么事？
...course of defensive magic. Yes?
课本没教如何使用防御咒语
There's nothing in here about using defensive spells?
使用咒语？
Using spells?
我的课堂上不需要使用咒语
Well, l can't imagine why you would need to use spells in my classroom.
我们不会使用咒语？
We're not gonna use magic?
你们会用安全的方法 学习防御魔法
You'll be learning about defensive spells in a secure, risk-free way.
那有什么用呢？ 遇到攻击一定会有危险
What use is that? lf we're attacked, it won't be risk-free.
想要发言的同学请先举手
Students will raise their hands when they speak in my class.
魔法部认为K
lt is the view of the Ministry...
学习基础理论K
...that a theoretical knowledge will be sufficient...
就能通过普等巫测
...to get you through your examinations...
毕竟这才是教学的目的
...which, after all, is what school is all about.
光凭理论 不能应付外面的危险
And how's theory supposed to prepare us for what's out there?
外面并没有危险啊
There is nothing out there, dear.
谁会攻击像你这样的小孩呢？
Who do you imagine wants to attack children like yourself?
不晓得，也许是伏地魔王
Oh, l don't know. Maybe Lord voldemort.
有一件事情我要说清楚
Now, let me make this quite plain.
有人告诉你们
You have been told...
有一个黑巫师又再度出现了
...that a certain dark wizard is at large once again.
- 这是个谎言 - 我没说谎，我看过他、对抗过他
-This is a lie. -lt's not a lie. l saw him. l fought him.
劳动服务，波特先生！
Detention, Mr. Potter.
你是说迪哥里 是突然暴毙的？
Cedric Diggory dropped dead of his own accord?
西追迪哥里的死 是一场意外悲剧
Cedric Diggory's death was a tragic accident.
伏地魔杀死他，你也知道
lt was murder. voldemort killed him.
够了 ！
Enough!
不要说了
Enough.
待会儿到我办公室来 波特先生
See me later, Mr. Potter. My office.
进来
Come in.
晚安，波特
Good evening, Mr. Potter.
坐吧
Sit.
我要你帮我写一些句子，波特
You're going to be doing some lines for me today, Mr. Potter.
不准用你的羽毛笔
No, not with your quill.
你要用我的特制羽毛笔
Going to be using a rather special one of mine.
现在
Now...
开始写 “我不可以说谎”
...l want you to write, ''l must not tell lies.''
要写几次？
How many times?
一直写到这句话 烙印在你心里
Well, let's say for as long as it takes for the message to sink in.
你没有给我墨水
You haven't given me any ink.
你不需要墨水
Oh, you won't need any ink.
（我不可以说谎）
怎么了？
Yes?
- 没什么 - 这才对
-Nothing. -That's right.
因为你在内心深处也知道K
Because you know, deep down...
这个惩罚是公平的
...you deserve to be punished.
对不对，波特？
Don't you, Mr. Potter?
继续吧
Go on.
（卫斯理兄弟）
（发烧糖）
摸鱼点心盒
-Skiving Snackboxes. -Sweets that make you ill.
- 会让你生病的糖果 - 这样才能随时请假
Get out of class whenever you like.
远离无聊的教室出去玩
Obtain hours of pleasure from unprofitable boredom.
要不要再来一块？
Care for another?
- 我又不是要你帮我写全部 - 拜托
-l'm not asking you to write all of it for me. -Please.
我正忙着准备讨厌的普等巫测
l've been busy studying for these stupid OWL exams.
我只能帮你写序言
l'll do the introduction. That's all.
妙丽，你是我认识最好的人
Hermione, you're honestly the most wonderful person l've ever met.
- 我再也不会对你没礼貌 - 才怪，你一定会
-And if l'm ever rude to you again.... -l'll know you've gone back to normal.
你的手怎么了？
What's wrong with your hand?
没什么
Nothing.
另一只手
The other hand.
- 你一定要告诉邓不利多 - 不
-You've got to tell Dumbledore. -No.
他已经有很多事情要烦恼
Dumbledore's got enough on his mind right now.
我不会让恩不里居得逞的
l don't want to give Umbridge the satisfaction.
拜托，她这是对你体罚
Bloody hell, Harry. The woman's torturing you.
- 如果让父母知道K - 问题是我没有父母，对吧？
-lf the parents knew about this.... -l haven't got any of those, have l, Ron?
哈利，你一定要向校长报告
Harry, you've got to report this.
- 事情很单纯，只要K - 不，并不单纯
-lt's perfectly simple. You're being-- -No, it's not.
妙丽，这件事一点也不单纯
Hermione, whatever this is, it's not simple.
你不会懂的
You don't understand.
解释给我们听呀
Then help us to.
亲爱的兽足
Dear Padfoot...
希望你一切安好
...I hope you're all right.
这里愈来愈冷 冬天肯定快到了
It's starting to get colder here. Winter is definitely on the way.
我虽然回到学校 却觉得更孤单
In spite of being back at Hogwarts, I feel more alone than ever.
你一定比别人更能够了解
I know you, of all people, will understand.
你好，哈利波特
Hello, Harry Potter.
- 你光着脚，不会冷吗？ - 有一点
-Your feet. Aren't they cold? -Bit.
我的鞋子好像都神秘消失了
Unfortunately, all my shoes have mysteriously disappeared.
我怀疑是水烟虫干的好事
l suspect Nargles are behind it.
- 他们是什么？ - 骑士坠鬼马
-What are they? -They're called Thestrals.
他们很温驯，不过K 人们回避他们，因为他们有点K
They're quite gentle, really, but people avoid them because they're a bit....
不一样
Different.
为什么其他人都看不到？
But why can't the others see them?
只有面对过死亡的人才看得到
They can only be seen by people who've seen death.
有你认识的人死了？
So you've known someone who's died, then?
我妈
My mum.
她是个了不起的女巫 但是她很喜欢做实验
She was quite an extraordinary witch, but she did like to experiment...
有一天她的咒语 出了严重意外
...and one day, one of her spells went badly wrong.
- 当时我九岁 - 很遗憾
-l was 9. -l'm sorry.
真的很不好受
Yes, it was rather horrible.
我有时候还会觉得难过 幸好我还有爸爸
l do feel very sad about it sometimes, but l've got Dad.
对了，我跟我爸都相信你
We both believe you, by the way.
那个我们不能说出名字的人回来了 你也对抗过他
That He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named is back, and you fought him...
魔法部和报社 阴谋对付你和校长
...and the Ministry and the Prophet are conspiring against you.
谢谢，你们好像是 唯一相信我的人
Thanks. lt seems you're about the only ones that do.
我觉得并不是这样
l don't think that's true.
不过我猜他要让你这么想
But l suppose that's how he wants you to feel.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
如果我是那个人
Well, if l were You-Know-Who...
我就会让你觉得被大家孤立
...l'd want you to feel cut off from everyone else...
只要你势单力孤K
...because if it's just you alone...
就构不成威胁
...you're not as much of a threat.
- 你就不能不吃东西吗？ - 人家肚子饿嘛
-Do you ever stop eating? -What? l'm hungry.
哈利
Harry.
我可以坐这里吗？
Can l join you?
教授，你对我有什么意见？
Pardon me, professor, but what exactly are you insinuating?
当你在处罚我的学生
l am merely requesting that when it comes to my students...
请你一定要遵守 学校现有的规定
...you conform to the prescribed disciplinary practices.
我没有听错吧
So silly of me, but it sounds...
你好像在质疑 我对我学生的权威K
...as if you're questioning my authority in my own classroom...
米奈娃
...Minerva.
我没这个意思，桃乐丝 我质疑的是你对学生的体罚
Not at all, Dolores, merely your medieval methods.
我觉得很遗憾
l am sorry, dear.
但是质疑我 就是质疑魔法部
But to question my practices is to question the Ministry...
也就是质疑部长本人
...and by extension, the minister himself.
我的包容力很强
l am a tolerant woman...
但是我绝不容忍对部长不忠心
...but the one thing l will not stand for is disloyalty.
不忠心
Disloyalty.
霍格华兹的情况 比我想像的更糟
Things at Hogwarts are far worse than l feared.
部长一定会马上采取紧急措施
Cornelius will want to take immediate action.
（教育章程第二十三条
恩不里居担任霍格华兹总督察）
（魔法部寻求教育改革）
邓不利多怎么样了？
What's happened to Dumbledore?
恩不里居改革了K
Having already revolutionized...
黑魔法防御教学
...the teaching of Defense Against the Dark Arts...
（家长支持魔法部的决定）
她身为霍格华兹总督察 拥有绝对的权力
...Dolores Umbridge will, as high inquisitor, have powers...
（夫子部长强调教育的重要性）
提高霍格华兹学校 下滑的水准
...to address the seriously falling standards at Hogwarts School.
我只有一个问题
Just one question, dear.
你担任这份教职有多久了？
You've been in this post how long, exactly?
你起初是申请 黑魔法防御教授，对不对？
You applied first for the Defense Against the Dark Arts post, is that correct?
是的
Yes.
但是你并没有成功
But you were unsuccessful?
很显然
Obviously.
（读书时间不可播放音乐）
（严禁使用卫斯理兄弟产品）
（随时保持良好服装跟礼仪）
请你为我预测将来好吗？
Could you please predict something for me?
你说什么？
l'm sorry?
嘴巴张大一点
Move those mouths.
来个小小的预言吧
One teensy little prophecy?
真可惜
Pity.
不，等一等 我好像看到什么了
No, wait. Wait, no. l think l do see something.
一件黑暗的事情
Yes, l do. Something dark.
你身陷极大的危险
You are in grave danger.
太好了
Lovely.
张秋，发生什么事？
Cho. What's going on?
崔老妮教授出事了
lt's Professor Trelawney.
十六年来我住在这里教书
Sixteen years l've lived and taught here.
霍格华兹是我的家
Hogwarts is my home.
你不能把我赶走
You can't do this.
老实说，我能
Actually, l can.
你有话要说吗？
Something you'd like to say?
我是有很多话想说出来
Oh, there are several things l would like to say.
别伤心K
There....
麦教授 麻烦你送崔教授回到学校
Professor McGonagall, might l ask you to escort Sybil back inside?
西碧，来吧
Sybil, dear. This way.
谢谢
Thank you.
邓不利多 容我提醒你K
Dumbledore, may l remind you that under the terms...
根据部长颁布的 教育章程第二十三条K
...of Educational Decree Number 23, as enacted by the minister--
你有权力开除学校老师
You have the right to dismiss my teachers.
但是你无权 把老师从学校赶走
You do not, however, have the authority to banish them from the grounds.
只有校长有这个权力
That power remains with the headmaster.
没多久了
For now.
你们都没有功课要做吗？
Don't you all have studying to do?
教授！
Professor.
Professor?
邓不利多教授！教授！
Professor Dumbledore. Professor!
邓不利多教授！
Professor Dumbledore.
龌龊邪恶的老巫婆
That foul, evil, old gargoyle.
我们根本没有学到防御术 也没有在准备普等巫测
We're not learning how to defend ourselves. We're not learning how to pass our OWLs.
她掌控了整个学校
She's taking over the entire school.
魔法部一向以 人民安全为第一优先
Security has been and will remain the Ministry's top priority.
另外，我们有证据显示
Furthermore, we have convincing evidence...
这些失踪事件
...that these disappearances are the work...
是恶名昭彰的天狼星所为
...of notorious mass murderer Sirius Black.
哈利
Harry.
天狼星
Sirius.
- 你来这里做什么？ - 回你的信啊
-What are you doing here? -Answering your letter.
你说你很担心恩不里居 她在干嘛？
You said you were worried about Umbridge. What's she doing?
训练你们杀杂种？
Training you to kill half-breeds?
- 她不准我们使用魔法 - 我一点也不意外
-She's not letting us use magic at all. -Well, l'm not surprised.
听说夫子不要你们 做任何战斗训练
The latest intelligence is that Fudge doesn't want you trained in combat.
战斗？
Combat?
他怕我们组成魔法师军团吗？
What does he think, we're forming some sort of wizard army?
这就是他的想法
That's exactly what he thinks.
他怕邓不利多 招募军队接管魔法部
That Dumbledore is assembling his own forces to take on the Ministry.
他愈来愈神经兮兮
He's becoming more paranoid by the minute.
其他人不希望 我跟你说这些事
The others wouldn't want me telling you this, Harry...
凤凰会的行动并不是很顺利
...but things aren't going at all well with the Order.
夫子用尽手段防堵真相
Fudge is blocking the truth at every turn...
这些失踪事件 跟上次完全一样
...and these disappearances are just how it started before.
伏地魔开始行动了
voldemort is on the move.
我们该怎么做？
Well, what can we do?
有人来了
Someone's coming.
抱歉我帮不上太多忙
l'm sorry l can't be of more help.
看来，现在K 你们必须靠自己了
But for now, at least, it looks like you're on your own.
他真的开始行动了
He really is out there, isn't he?
我们一定要能够保护自己
We've got to be able to defend ourselves.
恩不里居不肯教 那我们就找别人
And if Umbridge refuses to teach us how, we need someone who will.
哈利
Harry.
这太疯狂了，谁要让我教？
This is mad. Who'd wanna be taught by me?
大家都说我是疯子
l'm a nutter, remember?
乐观一点 你不会比那老蛤蟆糟
Look on the bright side: you can't be any worse than old toad face.
- 谢了，荣恩 - 我一定会挺你
-Thanks, Ron. -l'm here for you, mate.
有谁会来？
Who's supposed to be meeting us, then?
只有几个人
Just a couple of people.
这地方真不错
Lovely spot.
我觉得偏远的地方比较安全
Thought it would be safer off the beaten track.
羊仔，给我回来
Matey, come back here.
大家好
Hi.
大家都知道来这儿的目的
So you all know why we're here.
我们需要老师
We need a teacher.
真正的老师
A proper teacher.
用防御术对付过 黑魔王的老师
One who's had experience defending themselves against the Dark Arts.
- 为什么？ - 为什么？
-Why? -Why?
那个人回来了，笨蛋
Because You-Know-Who's back, you tosspot.
- 那是哈利说的 - 邓不利多也这么说
-So he says. -So Dumbledore says.
邓不利多 是因为哈利才这么说
So Dumbledore says because he says.
重点是证据在哪里？
The point is, where's the proof?
波特应该说出 迪哥里被杀的经过
lf Potter could tell us more about how Diggory got killed....
我不会谈这件事 如果你们因此而来，那可以走了
l'm not gonna talk about Cedric, so if that's why you're here, clear out now.
- 走吧，妙丽，他们全把我当怪胎 - 等一下
Come on, Hermione. They're here because they think l'm some sort of freak.
你真的会施展护法咒吗？
ls it true you can produce a Patronus Charm?
没错
Yes.
我亲眼看过
l've seen it.
真的假的？ 我不知道你会耶
Blimey, Harry. l didn't know you could do that.
他用邓不利多办公室K 的一把剑杀死蛇妖
And he killed a basilisk, with the sword in Dumbledore's office.
是真的
lt's true.
他一个人击退上百个催狂魔
Third year, he fought off about a hundred Dementors at once.
去年他还跟那个人 面对面打斗过
Last year, he really did fight off You-Know-Who in the flesh.
等等
Wait.
你们这么说 听起来好像很了不起
Look, it all sounds great when you say it like that...
老实说，我只是很幸运
...but the truth is, most of that was just luck.
我多半根本就不知所措 几乎每次都有人帮助
l didn't know what l was doing half the time. l nearly always had help.
- 他只是谦虚 - 我没有，妙丽
-He's just being modest. -No, Hermione, l'm not.
面对真正的敌人和上课不同
Facing this stuff in real life is not like school.
上课犯了错，能再试一次
ln school, if you make a mistake, you can just try again tomorrow.
可是在现实世界
But out there...
当你就快要被杀死
...when you're a second away from being murdered...
或是亲眼看着 朋友在你面前死去
...or watching a friend die right before your eyes....
你们不会了解那种感受
You don't know what that's like.
你说的对，哈利 我们是不了解
You're right, Harry, we don't.
我们不了解才需要你的帮助
That's why we need your help.
如果我们必须对抗K
Because if we're going to have any chance at beating...
伏地魔的话
...voldemort....
他真的回来了
He's really back.
（邓不利多的军队）
我们要找一个
Right. First we need to find a place to practice...
恩不里居查不到的地方练习
...where Umbridge won't find out.
- 尖叫屋 - 那里太小了
-The Shrieking Shack. -lt's too small.
- 禁忌的森林呢？ - 那里太恐怖了
-Forbidden Forest? -Not bloody likely.
哈利，被恩不里居发现会怎样？
Harry, what happens if Umbridge does find out?
谁在乎啊？
Who cares?
我是说K 违反校规很刺激耶
l mean, it's sort of exciting, isn't it, breaking the rules?
你是谁？ 你把妙丽怎么了？
Who are you and what have you done with Hermione?
起码今天有了一项正面收获
Anyway, at least we know one positive thing that came from today.
是什么？
What's that?
张秋从头到尾都盯着你看
Cho couldn't take her eyes off you, could she?
接下来这几天 我们要找几个K
Right. Over the next few days, we should each come up...
可以练习的地方
...with a couple of possibilities of places we can practice.
而且要确定不能被她找到
We've got to make sure, wherever it is, there's no chance she can find us.
没问题，哈利
Will do, Harry.
所有学生组织即刻解散
All student organizations are henceforth disbanded.
学生若有不从随即开除
Any student in noncompliance will be expelled.
走路要看路，隆巴顿
Watch where you're going, Longbottom.
你成功了，奈威 你找到万应室了
You've done it, Neville. You found the Room of Requirement.
什么？
The what?
这又叫做来去室
lt's also known as the Come and Go Room.
万应室只在最需要时 才会出现
The Room of Requirement only appears when a person has real need of it.
里面的配备完全符合你的需要
And it's always equipped for the seeker's needs.
需要上厕所也会出现？
So say you really needed the toilet....
你很白痴耶 不过就跟你说的差不多
Charming, Ronald. But, yes, that is the general idea.
太棒了，好像霍格华兹 希望我们起来抗争
lt's brilliant. lt's like Hogwarts wants us to fight back.
去去，武器走！
Expelliarmus.
我没救了
l'm hopeless.
你只是把魔杖甩得太用力 这样试试看，去去，武器走！
You're just flourishing your wand too much. Try it like this. Expelliarmus.
大家请把魔法部 核准的教科书抄写四遍
You will please copy the approved text four times...
才能确定通通记熟
...to ensure maximum retention.
- 考试时不准交谈 - 我看是不准用脑袋吧
-There will be no need to talk. -No need to think's more like it.
- 去去，武器走 - 魔杖收起来
-Expelliarmus. -Wands away.
昏击咒是最有用的咒语之一
Stunning is one of the most useful spells in your arsenal.
它是巫师的基本配备
lt's a wizard's bread and butter, really.
来吧，奈吉，你来试试看
So come on, then, Nigel. Give it your best shot.
咄咄失！
Stupefy!
很好，还不错 奈吉，做得好
Good. Not bad at all, Nigel. Well done.
别担心，我会轻一点
Don't worry. l'll go easy on you.
谢了，荣恩
Thanks, Ronald.
- 加油，荣恩K - 加油，荣恩K
-Come on, Ron. -Come on, Ron.
- 你一定办得到 - 加油，荣恩
-You can do it. -Come on, Ron.
- 我赌一西可 - 赌了
-One Sickle. -You're on.
咄咄失！
Stupefy.
- 谢了 - 闭嘴
-Thank you. -Shut up.
我是让她的 这是基本礼貌嘛
l let her do that. lt's good manners, isn't it?
我是真的故意让她的
lt was completely intentional.
（疑似从事不法活动者
需接受质询）
上来吧，想喝杯茶吗？
Up you come. Would you like a cup of tea?
专心对准固定的点 再试一次
Now, focus on a fixed point and try again.
去去，武器走！
Expelliarmus.
很好，注意力保持集中
very good. Keep your concentration.
非常好
Great.
再拿高一点
A little higher.
没事，我没事
l'm okay. l'm okay.
- 咄咄失！ - 咄咄失！
-Stupefy. -Stupefy.
学生欲加入督察小组 以求加分者
Those wishing to join the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit...
请向总督察室登记
...may sign up in the high inquisitor's office.
啾啾缩
Diminuendo.
努力很重要 但有一件事更重要
Working hard is important, but there's something that matters even more:
那就是相信自己
Believing in yourself.
- 去去，武器走！ - 倒倒吊！成了
-Expelliarmus. -Levicorpus. Got it.
想想看
Think of it this way.
史上每个伟大的巫师
Every great wizard in history has started out...
跟我们一样 一开始也是学生
...as nothing more than what we are now: students.
他们做得到，我们也行
lf they can do it, why not us?
- 咄咄失！ - 去去，武器走！
-Stupefy. -Expelliarmus.
去去，武器走K
Expelliarmus.
ハ
Reducto.
- 去去，武器走！ - 去去，武器走！
-Expelliarmus. -Expelliarmus.
去去，武器走！
Expelliarmus.
太好了，奈威 做得好
Fantastic, Neville. Well done, man.
这堂课就到此为止
So that's it for this lesson.
下一堂课是在圣诞节以后
Now, we're not gonna be meeting again until after the holidays.
回家以后 尽量自己偷偷练习
So just keep practicing on your own as best you can.
大家都表现得很好 真的很棒
And well done, everyone. Great, great work.
做得好
Well done, mate.
谢谢
Thanks.
圣诞节后再见
See you after Christmas.
我们到交谊厅等你，哈利
See you in the Common Room, Harry.
- 真的很谢谢你 - 不客气
-Thanks a lot, Harry. -No worries.
- 谢谢你 - 圣诞节快乐，不客气
-Thank you so much. -Not at all. Merry Christmas.
- 谢谢，圣诞节快乐 - 哈利，圣诞节快乐
-Thank you, Harry. -Thank you. Merry Christmas.
- 圣诞节快乐 - 圣诞节快乐，哈利
-Merry Christmas. -Have a good Christmas.
- 你也一样，露娜 - 哈利，我们一直在想
-Have a great Christmas, Luna. -We've been thinking.
可以在她的茶 放吐吐糖或发烧糖
We could always slip Umbridge some Puking Pastilles.
保证她脸上长满一堆有的没的
Or Fever Fudge. They give you massive, pus-filled boils--
听起来很棒，借过一下
Sounds great, guys. Would you excuse me?
你没事吧？ 听说前几天恩不里居为难你
Are you all right? l heard Umbridge gave you a rough time the other day.
对，我没事
Yeah. l'm okay.
我觉得很值得
Anyway, it's worth it.
只是K学习这些咒语
lt's just, learning all this...
让我一直猜 他到底会不会
...makes me wonder whether, if he'd known it....
西追吗？ 西追很懂这些咒语
Cedric did know this stuff.
他是高手
He was really good.
只是伏地魔比他厉害
lt's just, voldemort was better.
你是一个好老师，哈利
You're a really good teacher, Harry.
我以前用昏击咒都没成功过
l've never been able to stun anything before.
槲寄生
Mistletoe.
说不定长满了水烟虫
Probably full of Nargles, though.
水烟虫是什么？
What are Nargles?
我也不知道
No idea.
感觉怎么样？
Well, how was it?
湿湿的
Wet.
我是说她在哭
l mean, she was sort of crying.
你的吻功那么烂哦
That bad at it, are you?
哈利的技术应该在水准以上
l'm sure Harry's kissing was more than satisfactory.
最近张秋常常在哭
Cho spends half her time crying these days.
热吻也没让她开心起来
You'd think a bit of snogging would cheer her up.
你不懂她的感受吗？
Don't you understand how she must be feeling?
她很明显在为西追难过
Well, obviously she's feeling sad about Cedric...
又为喜欢哈利而亲他 感到内疚
...and confused about liking Harry and guilty about kissing him...
恩不里居还威胁要开除她妈
...conflicted because Umbridge might sack her mum from the Ministry...
又害怕普等巫测没有过 她每天都有很多烦恼
...and frightened of failing her OWLs because she's worrying about everything.
一个人有这么多烦恼 一定会疯掉
One person couldn't feel all that. They'd explode.
不要因为你没大脑 就这样讲别人
Just because you've got the emotional range of a teaspoon....
哈利
Harry.
伏地魔想找一样东西
Voldemort may be after something.
上次他没找到的东西
Something he didn't have last time.
哈利
Harry.
你在梦中 是站在受害人旁边
ln the dream, were you standing next to the victim...
还是旁观着整个过程？
...or looking down at the scene?
都不是，我觉得K
Neither. lt was like l....
教授，我是怎么了？
Will you please just tell me what's happening?
埃弗拉，今晚亚瑟负责守卫
Everard, Arthur's on guard duty tonight.
确认我方的人能找到他
Make sure he's found by the right people.
- 教授！ - 斐尼！
-Sir. -Phineas.
赶快去你在古里某街的划像
You must go to your portrait at Grimmauld Place.
告诉大家 亚瑟卫斯理受了重伤
Tell them that Arthur Weasley is gravely injured...
他的小孩会用 任意门钥匙赶过去
...and his children will be arriving there soon by Portkey.
找到他了，幸好他还活着
They've got him, Albus. lt was close, but they think he'll make it.
而且黑魔王没拿到东西
What's more, the Dark Lord failed to acquire it.
谢天谢地，现在我们要K
Oh, thank goodness. Next we need to--
看着我！
Look at me!
我到底是怎么回事？
What's happening to me?
你找我有事吗，校长？
You wished to see me, headmaster?
石内卜，我们不能再等了 甚至不能等到明天早上
Oh, Severus. l'm afraid we can't wait. Not even till the morning.
否则我们都有危险
Otherwise, we'll all be vulnerable.
黑魔王的心智
lt appears there's a connection...
跟你的心智似乎有联结
...between the Dark Lord's mind and your own.
我们不清楚 他是否发现了这个联结
Whether he is, as yet, aware of this connection is, for the moment, unclear.
希望他永远不会发现
Pray he remains ignorant.
如果他知道K
You mean, if he knows about it, then...
- 就知道我在想什么？ - 不但知道，还能控制你
-...he'll be able to read my mind? -Read it, control it...
把你逼疯
...unhinge it.
以前黑魔王喜欢
ln the past, it was often the Dark Lord's pleasure...
侵入猎物的心智
...to invade the minds of his victims...
利用幻觉 把这些人折磨到发疯
...creating visions designed to torture them into madness.
当他让一个人痛苦到受不了
Only after extracting the last exquisite ounce of agony...
开始求黑魔王把他杀掉
...only when he had them literally begging for death, would he finally...
黑魔王才会杀了他
...kill them.
只要小心使用 锁心咒的力量
Used properly, the power of Occlumency...
就能帮助你抵挡他的影响
...will help shield you from access or influence.
在上课时 我会试图穿透你的心智
ln these lessons, l will attempt to penetrate your mind.
你必须设法抵抗
You will attempt to resist.
准备好了
Prepare yourself.
破破心！
Legilimens.
专心，波特 集中注意力
Concentrate, Potter. Focus.
圣诞快乐
Ho, ho, ho. Merry Christmas.
好了
Here we go.
爸爸回来了
Daddy's back.
大家坐下来 很好，分礼物了
Sit down, everybody, sit down. That's it. Now, presents.
- 荣恩的礼物很大哦 - 超大的
-And a nice big box for Ron. -Big box for you. And....
弗雷，乔治，快打开
Fred and George. Come on, open up.
- 我想看你们的表情 - 对啊
-l want to see your faces. -Yes.
- 试试看 - 谢谢妈，太棒了
-Try it on. -Thanks, Mum. lt's perfect.
- 全都是你们要的礼物 - 是啊，谢谢你，妈
-Just what he wanted, actually. -Yeah. Right. Thanks, Mum.
来，大家把东西清一清
Come on, then, everybody. Let's clear this away.
哈利，哈利
Oh, Harry, Harry.
你来了
There you are.
- 圣诞快乐 - 谢谢
-Happy Christmas. -Thank you.
- 你能来真好 - 谢谢
-Lovely to have you with us. -Thank you.
好了，把酒拿给爸爸
Now, Daddy. Pass that to Daddy.
- 谢谢 - 大家都有礼物吗？
-Thank you. -Has everybody got?
弗雷？乔治？
Fred? George?
- 妙丽 - 来个圣诞敬酒
-Hermione. -A Christmas toast.
敬哈利波特
To Mr. Harry Potter...
没有他，我就不会在这里
...without whom l would not be here.
- 敬哈利 - 哈利
-Harry. -Harry.
哈利
Harry.
太好喝了，再多倒一点
That is delicious. l shall be needing some more of that.
别忘了去年的糗事
Daddy, don't forget last Christmas.
我搞不懂 你为什么不穿，荣恩
l can't understand why you don't want to wear it, Ronald.
因为穿起来像白痴
l look like a bloody idiot, that's why.
反正跟平常差不多
No more than usual, Ron.
你为什么不相信你妈的品味？
l don't know why....
你这坏小孩 厚颜无耻地站在这里
Nasty brat, standing there as bold as brass.
哈利波特 阻止黑魔王的男孩
Harry Potter, the boy who stopped the Dark Lord.
同时还是麻种和叛徒的朋友
Friend of Mudbloods and blood-traitors alike.
- 如果被我可怜的女主人知道K - 怪角 ！
-lf my poor mistress only knew.... -Kreacher!
念够了没？快滚！
That's enough of your bile. Away with you!
当然了，主人
Of course, master.
怪角生来就是要服侍 高贵的布莱克家
Kreacher lives to serve the noble house of Black.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
从我小时候 他就很没有礼貌
He never was very pleasant, even when l was a boy.
不过对我很好
Not to me, anyway.
你在这里长大的吗？
What, you grew up here?
这是我爸妈的房子
This is my parents' house.
我提供给邓不利多 当凤凰会总部
l offered it to Dumbledore as headquarters for the Order.
这大概是我唯一有用的地方
About the only useful thing l've been able to do.
这是布莱克家的族谱
This is the Black family tree.
我疯狂的堂妹
My deranged cousin.
我好恨他们
l hated the lot of them.
我的父母只认可 血统纯正的巫师
My parents with their pure-blood mania.
我妈在我逃家后弄成这样
My mother did that after l ran away.
有趣的女人
Charming woman.
那年我十六岁
l was 1 6.
你去了哪里？
Where did you go?
我去你爸那里
Round your dad's.
波特家随时都欢迎我
l was always welcome at the Potters' .
我在你身上看到他，哈利
l see him so much in you, Harry.
你们两个真的太像了
You are so very much alike.
这我就不确定
l'm not so sure.
天狼星，当我K
Sirius, when l was....
卫斯理先生被攻击时 我不只是旁观而已
When l saw Mr. Weasley attacked, l wasn't just watching.
我是那条蛇
l was the snake.
后来在邓不利多办公室
And afterwards, in Dumbledore's office...
有一刹那，我K我想K
...there was a moment when l wanted to--
我跟伏地魔之间有联结
This connection between me and voldemort.
我会不会变得跟他一样？
What if the reason for it is that l am becoming more like him?
我无时无刻都感到愤怒
l just feel so angry all the time.
当我经历过这些事情以后
And what if, after everything that l've been through...
我会不会走上寐罚 最后变得很坏？
...something's gone wrong inside me? What if l'm becoming bad?
我要你仔细听我说，哈利
l want you to listen to me very carefully, Harry.
你不是坏人
You're not a bad person.
你是很好的人 只是碰到一些坏事
You're a very good person who bad things have happened to.
你懂吗？
You understand?
况且世界不是 只有好人跟食死人
Besides, the world isn't split into good people and Death Eaters.
人的内心 同时有光明面跟黑暗面
We've all got both light and dark inside of us.
差别在于我们想运用哪一面
What matters is the part we choose to act on.
那才是真正的我们
That's who we really are.
哈利，该走了
Harry, time to go.
这一切结束后 我们就是一家人
When all this is over, we'll be a proper family.
等着瞧
You'll see.
来吧
Come on.
天狼星
真的？
Really?
哈利，哈利
Harry. Harry.
海格回来了
Hagrid's back.
对不起
l'm sorry.
我再说最后一次
l will say this one last time.
我命令你告诉我 你去了哪里
l'm ordering you to tell me where you've been.
我说过了，我去休养身体
l told you. l've been away for me health.
- 休养身体？ - 没错，我需要新鲜空气
-Your health? -Yeah. Bit of fresh air, you know.
是啊，身为养殖场管理人 大概很难呼吸到新鲜空气
Oh, yes. As gamekeeper, fresh air must be difficult to come by.
如果我是你 我不会指望待太久
lf l were you, l shouldn't get too used to being back.
最好连行李都先别打开
ln fact, l mightn't bother unpacking at all.
这是最高机密
This is top-secret, right?
邓不利多 派我去找巨人合作
Dumbledore sent me to parley with the giants.
巨人？
Giants?
你找到了吗？
You found them?
老实说他们一点也不难找 他们块头都很大
Well, they're not that hard to find, to be perfectly honest. They're so big, see?
我努力说服他们加入我们
l tried to convince them to join the cause.
不过我不是唯一 想拉拢他们的人
But l wasn't the only one that was trying to win them over.
- 还有食死人？ - 是的
-Death Eaters? -Yes.
他们想说服巨人 加入那个人
Trying to persuade them to join You-Know-Who.
- 结果呢？ - 我传达邓不利多的口信
-Did they? -l gave them Dumbledore's message.
也许有人会记得 他曾对他们很好
Suppose some of them remember he was friendly to them. l suppose.
他们却这样对你？
And they did this to you?
也不算是他们啦
Not exactly, no.
来吧，给你吃，笨狗狗
Oh, go on, you have it, then, you dozy dog.
外面改变很大
lt's changing out there.
就跟上次一样
Just like last time.
一场腥风血雨就要来临
There's a storm coming, Harry.
我们最好先做好准备
We'd all best be ready when she does.
我们确认了十个高度警戒囚犯
We have confirmed that 1 0 high-security prisoners...
（阿兹卡班大逃亡）
昨天傍晚的时候逃狱
...in the early hours of yesterday evening did escape.
（山雨欲来）
当然麻瓜的首相也收到警告
And of course, the Muggle prime minister has been alerted to the danger.
（魔法部激怒了人马）
我们强烈怀疑
We strongly suspect...
这场大逃狱
...that the breakout was engineered...
由曾经从阿兹卡班逃狱的人策划
...by a man with personal experience in escaping from Azkaban...
恶名昭彰的凶手天狼星布莱克
...notorious mass murderer Sirius Black...
逃犯贝拉雷斯壮的表哥
...cousin of escapee Bellatrix Lestrange.
（阿兹卡班大逃亡）
邓不利多警告过夫子 这种事可能会发生
Dumbledore warned Fudge this could happen.
他不敢面对现实 害大家遭殃
He's gonna get us all killed just because he can't face the truth.
哈利
Harry.
我K我想跟你道歉
l wanted to apologize.
连我妈都说 《预言家日报》不可靠
Now even me mum says the Prophet's version of things don't add up.
我想说的是K 我相信你
So, what l'm really trying to say is that l believe you.
奈威？
Neville?
十四年前K
Fourteen years ago...
一个叫贝拉雷斯壮的食死人
...a Death Eater named Bellatrix Lestrange...
对我爸妈使用酷刑咒
...used a Cruciatus Curse on my parents.
她折磨他们 拷问他们
She tortured them for information...
但是我爸妈都没屈服
...but they never gave in.
我很骄傲能当他们的儿子
l'm quite proud to be their son.
但我还没有准备好 让大家知道
But l'm not sure l'm ready for everyone to know just yet.
我保证我们会让他们感到骄傲
We're gonna make them proud, Neville. That's a promise.
想着让你感到坚强的回忆 最快乐的记忆
Make it a powerful memory, the happiest you can remember.
让它充满你的心 继续试，西莫
Allow it to fill you up. Keep trying, Seamus.
乔治，现在换你了
George, your turn now.
疾疾，护法现身
Expecto Patronum.
要制造完整形状的护法 很困难
A full-bodied Patronus is the most difficult to produce...
但是盾甲形状 也能对付各种敌人
...but shield forms can also be equally useful against a variety of opponents.
好厉害哦
Wow, that was really good.
很好，金妮
Fantastic, Ginny.
记住，只要专注于护法 就能保护你
Just remember, your Patronus can only protect you for as long as you stay focused.
保持专注，露娜
So focus, Luna.
想想最快乐的回忆
Think of the happiest thing you can.
疾疾，护法现身
Expecto Patronum.
- 我在努力 - 我知道，很好
-l'm trying. -l know. lt's good.
这是很高阶的魔法 大家都很棒
This is really advanced stuff, guys. You're doing so well.
疾疾，护法现身
Expecto Patronum.
我来帮大家省省事
l'll make short work of this.
大爆爆
Bombarda Maxima.
抓住他们
Get them.
我监视他们很久了
Been watching them for weeks.
你看， “邓不利多的军队”
And see, ''Dumbledore's Army'' ...
这证明我一开始 就跟你讲的事情
...proof of what l've been telling you right from the beginning, Cornelius.
你一直在散播谣言 说那个人要回来
All your fear-mongering about You-Know-Who...
骗不了我们的
...never fooled us for a minute.
我们看穿了你的谎言
We saw your lies for what they were:
你为了掌控魔法部 放出的烟幕弹
A smokescreen for your bid to seize control of the Ministry.
没错
Naturally.
不，教授 与他无关，主使是我
No, professor. He had nothing to do with it. lt was me.
你捍卫我的情操很高贵 但是事实很明显
Most noble of you, Harry, to shield me, but as has been pointed out...
上面写的是“邓不利多的军队” 不是“波特的军队”
...the parchment clearly says ''Dumbledore's Army,'' not ''Potter's.''
我指示哈利成立这个组织
l instructed Harry to form this organization.
我愿意为这些行为负起全责
And l, and l alone, am responsible for its activities.
派猫头鹰送信给《预言家日报》
Dispatch an owl to the Daily Prophet.
也许能赶上明早出刊
lf we hurry, we should still make the morning edition.
钝力、侠钩帽 押解邓不利多K
Dawlish, Shacklebolt, you will escort Dumbledore...
到阿兹卡班
...to Azkaban...
等待阴谋叛乱罪的审判
...to await trial for conspiracy and sedition.
事情恐怕没这么顺利
l thought we might hit this little snag.
你们似乎误以为我会K
You seem to be laboring under the delusion that l'm going to--
怎么说呢？
What was the phrase?
束手就擒
--come quietly.
不过我告诉你们
Well, l can tell you this:
我完全无意去阿兹卡班
l have no intention of going to Azkaban.
说够了吧
Enough of this.
立刻押走
Take him.
部长，你虽然不喜欢他
Well, you may not like him, minister...
不过不能否认
...but you can't deny...
邓不利多很有格调
...Dumbledore has got style.
（恩不里居取代邓不利多
接任霍格华兹学校校长一职）
男女学生之间 必须保持八英寸的距离
Boys and girls are not permitted to be within eight inches of each other.
学生想加入督察小组 以求加分K
Those wishing to join the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit....
疑似从事不法活动者 需接受质询
Students will be submitted to questioning about suspected illicit activities.
拒绝合作的学生将被开除
Any student in noncompliance will be expelled.
哈利
Harry.
你尽力了 没人对付得了老巫婆
You did everything you could. No one could win against that old hag.
就连邓不利多也没料到
Even Dumbledore didn't see this coming.
就算有错，也是我们的错
Harry, if it's anyone's fault, it's ours.
是我们说服你这么做的
Yeah, we talked you into it.
可是我也同意了
Yeah, but l agreed.
我很努力想要帮忙 却只让情况变得更糟
l tried so hard to help, and all it's done is make things worse.
反正这些都不重要了
Anyway, that doesn't matter anymore.
我不玩了 继续下去只会让你太在乎
Because l don't want to play anymore. All it does is make you care too much.
愈是在乎 就必须失去愈多
And the more you care, the more you have to lose.
- 所以我们最好K - 最好怎样？
-So maybe it's just better to.... -To what?
管好自己就好
To go it alone.
海格
Hagrid.
他要带我们去哪里？
Any idea where he's taking us?
海格，你干嘛不直接说？
Hagrid, why can't you just tell us?
我没有看过人马这么激动
l've never seen the centaurs so riled.
他们正常的时候 就够危险了
And they're dangerous at the best of times.
魔法部继续限制他们的地盘
The Ministry restricts their territory much more...
他们就要起来暴动了
...they'll have a full uprising on their hands.
到底是怎么回事？
Hagrid, what's going on?
抱歉要搞得这么神秘兮兮
l'm sorry to be so mysterious, you three.
我也不想烦你们 不过邓不利多不在了
l wouldn't be bothering you at all with it, but with Dumbledore gone...
我也随时可能会被开除
...l'll likely be getting the sack any day now.
我不能没说出他的事就走掉
And l just couldn't leave without telling someone about him.
呱啦
Grawpy.
我在下面，你这小傻瓜
Down here, you great buffoon.
小呱啦
Grawpy.
我带朋友来找你
Brought you some company.
我不能丢下他不管
l couldn't just leave him, because--
因为他是我弟弟
Because he's my brother.
老天爷
Blimey.
其实是不同爸爸
Well, half brother, really.
他不会伤害任何人 只是有一点过动
He's completely harmless, just like l said. Little high-spirited, is all.
- 小呱啦，这样很没礼貌 - 海格，快想办法
-Grawpy, that is not polite. -Hagrid, do something.
我跟你说过，不准抓人
We talked about this. You do not grab, do you?
她是你的新朋友妙丽
That's your new friend, Hermione.
呱啦
Grawpy.
Grawp.
把我放下来
Put me down.
快点
Now.
你没事吧？
You all right?
没事
Fine.
他只是需要严格管教
Just needs a firm hand, is all.
你多了一个仰慕者
l think you've got an admirer.
离她远一点，听到没？
You just stay away from her, all right?
他自己会找东西吃
He gets his own food and all.
我不在时 他需要人陪伴
lt's company he'll be needing when l'm gone.
你们会照顾他，对吧？
You will look after him, won't you?
我是他唯一的亲人
l'm the only family he's got.
觉得很伤感吗？
Feeling sentimental?
- 这是我的隐私 - 挡不住我的
-That's private. -Not to me.
你不进步的话 也挡不住黑魔王
And not to the Dark Lord, if you don't improve.
你的回忆 都是他对付你的利器
Every memory he has access to is a weapon he can use against you.
被他入侵绝对撑不了两秒
You won't last two seconds if he invades your mind.
你就跟你爸一样
You're just like your father.
懒惰又自大
Lazy, arrogant.
- 不准说我爸的坏话！ - 软弱
-Don't say a word against my father. -Weak.
- 我才不软弱！ - 那就证明给我看
-l'm not weak. -Then prove it.
控制你的情绪
Control your emotions.
训练你的心智
Discipline your mind.
破破心
Legilimens.
哈利
Harry.
天狼星
Sirius.
我快吐了
I may vomit.
快住手
Stop it.
这就是你所谓的控制力吗？
ls this what you call control?
我们练好久了，我需要休息
We've been at it for hours. lf l could just rest.
黑魔王从不休息
The Dark Lord isn't resting.
你和天狼星还真像
You and Black, you're two of a kind.
像多愁善感的小孩子一样 一直抱怨人生痛苦又不公平
Sentimental children forever whining about how bitterly unfair your lives have been.
你要搞清楚 人生本来就不公平
Well, it may have escaped your notice, but life isn't fair.
你老爸也知道 事实上，他对我就很不公平
Your blessed father knew that. ln fact, he frequently saw to it.
- 我父亲是个伟大的人 - 你爸是下三滥
-My father was a great man. -Your father was a swine.
- 破破心 - 破心护
-Legilimens. -Protego.
拜托，月影，兽足
Come on, Moony, Padfoot.
石内卜 去去，武器走
Snape. Expelliarmus.
漂亮，詹姆
Nice one, James.
- 爸 - 喷喷障
-Dad. -Impedimenta.
鼻涕卜，脏兮兮K
Snivellus Greasy. Snivellus Greasy.
有没有人想看 我帮鼻涕卜脱裤子？
Right. Who wants to see me take off Snivelly's trousers?
鼻涕卜，脏兮兮K
Snivellus Greasy. Snivellus Greasy.
够了
Enough.
你这堂课已经结束了
Your lessons are at an end.
我K
l--
给我滚出去
Get out.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 麦可
-What's your name? -Michael.
不要难过好不好
Your hand's gonna be fine, Michael.
其实没有看起来那么严重
Yeah. lt's not as bad as it seems. See?
你看，我的消了
lt's fading already.
对啊，你看我的也消了 过一阵子就不会痛了
You can hardly see ours anymore, and the pain stops after a while.
我之前已经说过了，波特
As l told you once before, Mr. Potter...
顽皮的学生就应该得到惩罚
...naughty children deserve to be punished.
你知道吗，乔治
You know, George...
我一直觉得我们的未来在外面 而不是在学校里面
...l've always felt our futures lay outside the world of academic achievement.
弗雷，我想的跟你一模一样
Fred, l've been thinking exactly the same thing.
（安静 五年级普等巫测进行中
考试项目 ：咒语理论）
好耶，教授！
All right, professor!
开始
Here you go.
好了跟我说一声
Ready when you are.
我需要那个预言
l need that prophecy.
你杀了我再说
You'll have to kill me.
我会的 不过你得先去帮我拿来
Oh, l will. But first, you will fetch it for me.
咒咒虐！
Crucio.
天狼星
Sirius.
哈利，你确定吗？
Harry, are you sure?
我看到了 就像我看到卫斯理先生
l saw it. lt's just like with Mr. Weasley.
那是我最近一直梦到的门
lt's the door l've been dreaming about.
只是我想不起来在哪里看过
l couldn't remember where l'd seen it before.
天狼星说伏地魔想找什么东西
Sirius said voldemort was after something.
他上次没找到的东西 东西就在神秘部门里头
Something he didn't have the last time, in the Department of Mysteries.
哈利，拜托，听我说
Harry, please, just listen.
如果伏地魔是故意 让你看到的话，怎么办？
What if voldemort meant for you to see this?
如果他想利用伤害天狼星 来抓你怎么办？
What if he's only hurting Sirius because he's trying to get to you?
如果是真的 我就该让天狼星死？
What if he is? l'm supposed to just let him die?
妙丽，他是我现在唯一的亲人
Hermione, he's the only family l've got left.
我们该怎么办？
What do we do?
用呼噜网赶过去
We'll have to use the Floo Network.
恩不里居监视所有的烟囱
Umbridge has the chimneys under surveillance.
她自己的就没有
Not all of them.
阿咯哈姆啦
Alohomora.
你们去警告凤凰会
Alert the Order if you can.
- 你疯了吗？我们也要去 - 这太危险了
-Are you mental? We're going with you. -lt's too dangerous.
你到底什么时候才会了解？ 我们大家是一体的
When are you going to get it into your head? We're in this together.
你说的一点都没错
That you are.
这小子想帮卫斯理家的女孩
Caught this one trying to help the Weasley girl.
你要去找邓不利多 对不对？
You were going to Dumbledore, weren't you?
- 不对 - 骗子
-No. -Liar.
- 你找我吗，校长？ - 没错，石内卜
-You sent for me, headmistress? -Snape, yes.
我要知道答案 不管他想不想说
The time has come for answers, whether he wants to give them to me or not.
你的吐真剂带来了吗？
Have you brought the veritaserum?
你询问学生时 把我的库存用完了
l'm afraid you've used up all my stores interrogating students.
最后一次是用在张秋身上
The last of it on Miss Chang.
如果你是想毒死他 那没问题
Unless you wish to poison him--
我到时候一定会很同情他
And l assure you, l would have the greatest sympathy if you did.
但是我没有吐真剂
--l cannot help you.
他抓了兽足
He's got Padfoot.
他在藏东西的地方 把兽足抓走
He's got Padfoot at the place where it's hidden.
兽足？什么是兽足？ 藏什么东西？
Padfoot? What is Padfoot? Where what is hidden?
怎么回事？他在说些什么？
What is he talking about, Snape?
我哪知道？
No idea.
好吧
very well.
你让我别无选择，波特
You give me no choice, Potter.
这件事关系着魔法部的安全
As this is an issue of Ministry security...
你让我没有K
...you leave me with...
选择的余地
...no alternative.
酷刑咒应该可以让你说实话
The Cruciatus Curse ought to loosen your tongue.
那是违法的
That's illegal.
只要别让夫子知道就没问题
What Cornelius doesn't know won't hurt him.
快告诉她，哈利！
Tell her, Harry!
告诉我什么？
Tell me what?
你不告诉她在哪里K
Well, if you won't tell her where it is...
那我告诉她
...l will.
什么东西？在哪里？
Where what is?
邓不利多的秘密武器
Dumbledore's secret weapon.
还有多远？
How much further?
不远了
Not far.
东西得藏在 不会被学生撞见的地方
lt had to be somewhere students wouldn't find it accidentally.
你想干嘛？
What are you doing?
随机应变
lmprovising.
怎么样？
Well?
这个武器在哪里？
Where is this weapon?
根本没有武器，对不对？
There isn't one, is there?
你只是想耍我
You were trying to trick me.
知道吗K
You know...
我最讨厌小孩子
...l really hate children.
这里没有你们的事情，人马 这是魔法部的事情
You have no business here, centaur. This is a Ministry matter.
放下你们的武器
Lower your weapons.
我警告你们 法律规定，智慧不如人类的生物K
l warn you, under the law, as creatures of near-human intelligence....
破心护
Protego.
好大的胆子
How dare you?
肮脏的杂种
Filthy half-breed.
绳绳禁
Incarcerous.
拜托！快住手！拜托！
Please. Please stop it. Please.
现在开始 你们给我规矩一点
Now, enough. l will have order.
你们这些畜牲
You filthy animal.
知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who l am?
不要这样对他 这不是他的错
Leave him alone. lt's not his fault.
不要，他什么都不懂
No, he doesn't understand.
快想办法告诉他们 我不是故意要伤害他们
Potter, do something. Tell them l mean no harm.
抱歉，教授
l'm sorry, professor.
我不可以说谎
But l must not tell lies.
你们在干什么？
What are you doing?
我是魔法部政务次长 桃乐思恩不里居
l am Senior Undersecretary Dolores Jane Umbridge.
放开我！
Let me go!
谢谢你，呱啦
Thank you, Grawp.
妙丽，妙丽，天狼星
Hermione. Hermione, Sirius.
- 你们是怎么逃出来的？ - 利用吐吐糖，还满恶心的
-How'd you get away? -Puking Pastilles. lt wasn't pretty.
我说我肚子饿了想吃糖果
Told them l was hungry, wanted some sweets.
他们叫我别作梦 然后抢去吃掉
They told me to bugger off and ate the lot themselves.
这招很聪明，荣恩
That was clever, Ron.
- 我只是展现实力 - 这招太妙了
-Has been known to happen. -lt was brilliant.
我们怎么去伦敦？
So how are we getting to London?
我很感激你们大家 为我做的这些事
Look, it's not that l don't appreciate everything you've done, all of you...
但我已经替你们 惹了不少麻烦
...but l've got you into enough trouble as it is.
邓不利多的军队 应该开始玩真的了
Dumbledore's Army's supposed to be about doing something real.
难道你不遵守诺言吗？
Or was that all just words to you?
你根本就不需要孤军奋战
Maybe you don't have to do this all by yourself, mate.
那我们应该怎么去伦敦？
So how are we going to get to London?
当然是用飞的啊
We fly, of course.
神秘部门
Department of Mysteries.
神秘部门到了
This is it.
九十二、九十三
Ninety-two. Ninety-three.
九十四
Ninety-four.
九十五
Ninety-five.
- 他应该在这里 - 哈利
-He should be here. -Harry.
这上面有你的名字
lt's got your name on it.
拥有消灭黑魔王力量的人 即将降临
The one with the power to vanquish the Dark Lord approaches.
黑魔王将标记他为己之同等
And the Dark Lord shall mark him as his equal...
但他拥有黑魔王未知的力量
...but he shall have power the Dark Lord knows not.
两者之中必有一人 死于另一人之手
For neither can live while the other survives.
哈利
Harry.
天狼星在哪儿？
Where's Sirius?
你应该学习分辨梦境K
You know, you really should learn to tell the difference between dreams...
还有真实
...and reality.
你看到的 只是黑魔王安排的划面
You saw only what the Dark Lord wanted you to see.
把预言交给我吧
Now, hand me the prophecy.
你敢动手我就把它打破
lf you do anything to us, l'll break it.
他知道游戏规则呢
He knows how to play.
可爱的小宝贝
ltty, bitty baby.
波特
Potter.
贝拉雷斯壮
Bellatrix Lestrange.
奈威隆巴顿 爸妈还好吗？
Neville Longbottom, is it? How's Mum and Dad?
好多了 有人要帮他们报仇了
Better, now they're about to be avenged.
大家先冷静一下
Now, let's everybody just calm down...
好吗？
...shall we?
我们要的只是预言而已
All we want is that prophecy.
伏地魔为什么 要我来拿这东西？
Why did voldemort need me to come and get this?
你竟敢直呼他的名字
You dare speak his name?
你这肮脏的混血！
You filthy half-blood!
没关系，他只不过是好奇宝宝
lt's all right. He's just a curious lad, aren't you?
只有跟预言有关的人 才能拿到预言
Prophecies can only be retrieved by those about whom they are made.
这是你走运的地方，真的
Which is lucky for you, really.
你难道从来没有想过
Haven't you always wondered...
为什么你跟黑魔王一直有联结？
...what was the reason for the connection between you and the Dark Lord?
为什么你是婴儿时候
Why he was unable to kill you...
他杀不掉你？
...when you were just an infant?
你不想知道 你头上疤痕的秘密吗？
Don't you want to know the secret of your scar?
所有的答案 都在你手里，波特
All the answers are there, Potter, in your hand.
你只要K
All you have to do...
把它交给我
...is give it to me.
我自然会告诉你一切
Then l can show you everything.
我已经等了十四年
l've waited 1 4 years.
我知道
l know.
再多等一下也无所谓 上，咄咄失！
l guess l can wait a little longer. Now. Stupefy.
咄咄失！
Stupefy.
倒倒吊
Levicorpus.
整整石化
Petrificus Totalus.
做得好，奈威
Well done, Neville.
咄咄失！
Stupefy.
- 咄咄失！ - 咄咄失！
-Stupefy. -Stupefy.
咄咄失
Stupefy.
ハ！
Reducto.
快跑去门口
Get back to the door.
神秘部门 这地方果然很诡异
Department of Mysteries. They got that bit right, didn't they?
有声音
The voices.
听得出来说什么吗？
Can you tell what they're saying?
根本没声音，哈利
There aren't any voices, Harry.
我们快离开
Let's get out of here.
我也听到了
l hear them too.
哈利，那只是 一条空走道而已
Harry, it's just an empty archway.
拜托，哈利
Please, Harry.
快到我后面！
Get behind me.
你还真的相信
Did you actually believe...
你真的天真到以为
...or were you truly naive enough to think...
你们这些小孩能打败我们吗？
...that children stood a chance against us?
我给你一个简单的选择，波特
l'll make this simple for you, Potter.
现在就把预言给我
Give me the prophecy now...
不然就看着你的朋友死
...or watch your friends die.
不要给他，哈利
Don't give it to him, Harry.
不要碰我的教子
Get away from my godson.
听我说，我要你 带其他人离开
Now, listen to me. Take the others and get out of here.
不行，我要跟你在一起
What? No, l'm staying with you.
哈利，你表现得很棒
You've done beautifully.
接下来就交给我吧
Now, let me take it from here.
布莱克
Black.
去去，武器走！
Expelliarmus!
表现不错，小詹姆
Nice one, James.
阿哇炜炖
Avada Kedavra.
不！
No. No.
我杀了天狼星
l killed Sirius Black.
- 快来啊 - 咒咒虐
-You coming to get me? -Crucio.
施咒语要认真，哈利
You've got to mean it, Harry.
她杀了天狼星，她该死
She killed him. She deserves it.
你知道那咒语，哈利
You know the spell, Harry.
快点
Do it.
真是软弱
So weak.
你真愚蠢 选择今晚来这里，汤姆
lt was foolish of you to come here tonight, Tom.
正气师都赶来了
The Aurors are on their way.
等他们到达时 我已经走了，而你K
By which time l shall be gone, and you...
也已经死了
...shall be dead.
你输了，老头
You've lost, old man.
哈利
Harry.
真是软弱
So weak.
不堪一击
So vulnerable.
看着我
Look at me.
哈利，你不是这样的人
Harry, it isn't how you are alike.
你不是这种人
lt's how you are not.
哈利
Harry?
你才是软弱的人
You're the weak one...
你永远不懂 什么是爱跟友情
...and you'll never know love or friendship.
我为你感到悲哀
And l feel sorry for you.
你真是愚蠢，哈利波特
You're a fool, Harry Potter.
你将会失去所有的一切
And you will lose everything.
他回来了
He's back.
（证实邓不利多、波特所言）
（部长请辞？）
（恩不里居停职接受调查）
（那个不能说出名字的人回来了）
（霍格华兹校长复职）
我了解你的感受，哈利
l know how you feel, Harry.
你不了解
No, you don't.
全都是我的错
lt's my fault.
不对，是我的错
No, the fault is mine.
我知道伏地魔迟早会知道
l knew it was only a matter of time...
他跟你之间的联系
...before voldemort made the connection between you.
我以为只要跟你保持距离 就像这一整年
l thought by distancing myself from you, as l have done all year...
他就不会想掌控你 你也比较能得到保护
...he'd be less tempted, and therefore you might be more protected.
预言说
The prophecy said:
“两者之中必有一人 死于另一人之手”
''Neither one can live while the other one survives.''
表示有一个人 最后要杀死对方
lt means one of us is gonna have to kill the other, in the end.
对
Yes.
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
跟你想救天狼星的原因一样
For the same reason you tried to save Sirius.
跟你朋友救你的原因一样
The same reason your friends saved you.
经过这些年 你经历了这么多折磨
After all these years, after all you've suffered...
我不想再加重你的痛苦
...l didn't want to cause you any more pain.
因为我太关心你了
l cared too much about you.
你怎么没有参加宴会？
How come you're not at the feast?
我的东西全都不见了 应该又是被其他人藏起来了
Lost all my possessions. Apparently people have been hiding them.
真是过分
That's awful.
其实还蛮好玩的
Oh, it's all good fun.
不过明天要回家 我得快找回来
But as it's the last night, l really do need them back.
需要我帮你找吗？
Do you want any help finding them?
我为你教父的事感到难过
l'm sorry about your godfather, Harry.
确定不需要我帮忙吗？
Are you sure you don't want any help looking?
没关系啦
That's all right.
反正我妈妈总是说K
Anyway, my mum always said...
失去的最后都能回到我们身边
...the things we lose have a way of coming back to us in the end.
虽然不见得是我们期待的方式
lf not always in the way we expect.
我还是去吃一点布丁好了
Think l'll just go have some pudding.
我一直在想 邓不利多跟我说的事
l've been thinking about something Dumbledore said to me.
什么事？
What's that?
虽然我们必须面对一场战斗
That even though we've got a fight ahead of us...
但是我们拥有 伏地魔没有的东西
...we've got one thing that voldemort doesn't have.
是什么？
Yeah?
值得我们捍卫的一切
Something worth fighting for.
导演：大卫叶慈
编剧：迈克高登堡
制片 ：大卫海曼 大卫巴伦
原著小说： ⒇K罗琳
主演：丹尼尔雷德克里夫
主演：鲁帕葛林
主演：艾玛怀森
主演：海伦娜波汉卡特
主演：罗比柯崔恩
主演：雷夫范恩斯
主演：麦可甘柏
主演：布雷登葛利森
主演：理查葛瑞芬
主演：杰森艾萨克
主演：盖瑞欧德曼
主演：艾伦瑞克曼
主演：费欧娜萧
主演：玛姬史密斯
主演：伊美黛史道顿
主演：大卫休理斯
主演：艾玛汤普逊
片名：哈利波特： 凤凰会的密令